(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T21:52:29.560552",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
まわる まわる まわる ルーナ
Spinning, spinning, spinning, Luna!
まわる まわる まわる ルーナルナ
Spinning, spinning, spinning, Luna, Luna!
まわる まわる まわる ルーナ
Spinning, spinning, spinning, Luna!
まわる まわる 地球を ぐるぐるま
Spinning, spinning the Earth round and round
またたく間に街中が まわる まわる あたまぐるぐる
In the blink of an eye, the town spins round!
幕が上がり祭りの始まり まわる まわる 迷いをひらいたら
The curtain rises, the festival begins. Open your eyes and spin!
回りすぎなら世界のが闇が みんなを包む恐怖乱舞
If we spin too much, the world's darkness wraps around us
大丈夫守るから まわる まわる 迷いを開いたら
It's alright, I'll protect you. Spin, spin, open your hesitation!
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って (もっと)
Spin, spin, spin, spin around (more!)
もっとぐるぐる回って (もっともっと)
Spin round and round more (more and more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って (もっと) みんなぐるぐる回って (もっと)
Spin round and round everyone spin around (more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って (ずっと)
Spin round and round, spin more and more (always)
ぐるぐるぐるぐるまわるーナ (やぁ)
Spinning round and round, Mawalu-na! (Yay!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って もっとぐるぐる笑って (もっともっと)
Smile round and round, smile more (more and more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる踊って みんなぐるぐる踊って (もっと)
Dance round and round, everyone dance (more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐるそうやって もっとぐるぐる回って ずっとぐるぐるまわるーナ (やぁ)
That's how we spin, keep spinning round and round, Mawalu-na! (Yay!)
回りすぎなら世界のが闇が みんなを包む恐怖乱舞
If we spin too much, the world's darkness wraps around everyone in a chaotic dance
大丈夫守るから まわる まわる 地球は回り初めて
It's alright, I'll protect you. Spin, spin, the Earth starts to turn...
いつでもこのまま まわる みんなに幸せを...
Always stay like this, spinning happiness to everyone...
まわりつづくまわるーナ ますますます社会がぐるぐる まー…あれ？ (わぁ)
Continuing to spin, Mawalu-na. Society spins more and more... Wait? (Wah!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って (もっと) もっとぐるぐる回って (もっともっと)
Spin, spin, spin, spin around (more), spin more and more!
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐる回って (もっと)
Spin round and round, everyone spin around (more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って (もっともっと)
Spin round and round, spin more and more!
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って ずっとぐるぐるまわるーナ (やぁ)
Spin round and round, keep spinning Mawalu-na! (Yay!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って もっとぐるぐる笑って (もっともっと)
Smile round and round, smile more and more!
ぐるぐるぐるぐる踊って みんなぐるぐる踊って (もっと)
Dance round and round, everyone dance (more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐるそうやって もっとぐるぐる回って (もっともっと)
That's how we spin, keep spinning round and round (more and more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って ずっとぐるぐるまわるーナ (やぁ)
Smile round and round, keep spinning Mawalu-na! (Yay!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って (もっともっと)
Spin round and round, spin more and more!
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐる回って (もっと)
Spin round and round, everyone spin around (more!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って (もっともっと)
Spin round and round, spin more and more!
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って ずっとぐるぐるまわるーナ んな〜
Spin round and round, keep spinning Mawalu-na, nna~!
(ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっと)
(Spin round and round, more!)
(ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って んな〜)
(Spin round and round, nna~!)
ぐるぐるまわる まわるーナ! (やぁ)
Spinning round and round, Mawalu-na! (Yay!)
おっ、うしろにールナとー、
Oh, behind Luna and...
このっ、両側にー 帰ってきたっぱなー？
on both sides, who returned?
ベイビーノーマルーが あらわれたけど みんなたーと思ってなー？
Baby Normals appeared, but did you all think so too?
こちらはね、去年のサンタさんのステージで
This is, from last year's Santa stage,
ルナたんがね、ぐるぐる回る、回るのをね、歌ったんだけどー
Luna-tan, you know, spinning round and round, I sang that, but...
なんと、なんと今日、このライブの後にぐるぐる回る回るのー、MVが公開されるのだーい！
Guess what? Today, after this live, the MV for "Spinning Round and Round" will be released!
あーい！
Yay!
みんな、たぶんずっと待っててくれたと思うので、
Everyone, I'm sure you've been waiting for a long time,
楽しみににしててほしいのだー！
so I hope you're looking forward to it!
では、そろそろ、移動しようかなー
Well then, shall we move along soon?
ルナたんわ、きょう、宇宙に行くのだーい！
Today, Luna-tan is going to space!
いっくのらたーいむ！
It's nanora time!
水面が揺るぐ
The water's surface quivers
風の輪が広がる
A ring of wind spreads
触れ合った指先の青い電流
The blue current of touching fingertips
見つめあうだけで
Just by gazing at each other
孤独な加速度が
lonely acceleration
一瞬に砕け散る
shatters in an instant
あなたが好きよ
I love you
透明な真珠のように
Like clear pearls
宙に浮く涙
tears floating in the air
悲劇だってかまわない
It's a tragedy and it doesn't matter
あなたと生きたい
I want to live with you
キラッ！
Sparkle!
流星にまたがって
Riding a shooting star
あなたに急降下 ah ah
I dive toward you, ah ah
濃紺の星空に
In the dark blue starlit sky
私たち花火みたい
We're like fireworks
心が光の矢を放つ
Our hearts shoot an arrow of light
会話などなしに
Without any conversation
内側に潜って
diving inward
考えが読み取れる
I can read your thoughts
不思議な夜
on this mysterious night
あなたの名 呪文みたいに
Your name is like a spell
無限のリピート
repeated infinitely
惜しんで手の甲に
Reluctantly, on the back of my hand
爪をたててみる
I try digging my nails in
キラッ！
Sparkle!
身体ごと透き通り
My whole body is transparent
絵のように漂う uh uh
drifting like a painting, uh uh
けし粒の生命でも
Even as a speck of life
私たち瞬いてる
we are twinkling
魂に銀河 雪崩れてく
Galaxies avalanche into our souls
流星にまたがって
Riding a shooting star
あなたは急上昇 oh oh
you soar upward, oh oh
濃紺の星空に
In the dark blue starlit sky
私たち花火みたい
We're like fireworks
心が光の矢を放つ
Our hearts shoot an arrow of light
Our hearts shoot an arrow of light.
けし粒の生命でも
Even as a speck of life,
私たち瞬いてる
we are twinkling.
魂に銀河 雪崩れてく
Snow falls into the galaxy of our souls.
わあ、すごーくーして、新しいステージに来たのだよー！
Wah, super-duper, we've come to a new stage, nodesu!
宇宙だ！地球だ！
It's space! It's Earth!
地球は青かったのだねー！
The Earth was blue, nodesu!
そしてこのでっかいお城な！すごすぎだ！
And this huge castle! It's amazing!
そしてここにキラキラのシャンデリアが空いて…真ん中にはかぼちゃのウナタンの馬車がていねいとかわいく置いてあり！
And here, a sparkly chandelier is open... and in the middle, Unatan's pumpkin carriage is carefully and cutely placed!
そしてそして、こっちには…
And then, over here...
正面…のチクチクのコンペイトウが置いてあるのだねー！
The spiky konpeito is placed right in front, nodesu!
いやあ、移動大変だったのだなここまで！
Man, it was a tough trip getting all the way here!
みんなさっきのロケット、ホログラで乗ってたのを覚えてるのだな？
Everyone remember riding that rocket in hologram earlier?
ロケットもすごかったでしょー！
The rocket was amazing, right?
あとね、見てほしいのはこれ！今日のテーマ、ムーンギャラクシー！
And hey, what I want you to see is this! Today's theme, Moon Galaxy!
今日は宇宙や星にまつわる歌をね、たくさん！たくさん歌うのだー！
Today, I'm going to sing lots and lots of songs related to space and stars!
いつもどおりのある日のこと
On a day just like any other,
君は突然立ち上がり言った
you suddenly stood up and said,
「今夜星を見に行こう」
"Let's go look at the stars tonight."
「たまには良いこと言うんだね」
"You say something nice every now and then."
なんてみんなして言って笑った
is what everyone said, laughing together.
明かりもない道を バカみたいにしゃかりきに歩いた
We walked frantically down a path without any lights, like fools.
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に 押し潰されないように
So as not to be crushed by the loneliness and anxiety we held inside,
真っ暗な世界から見上げた 夜空は星が降るようで
looking up from a pitch-black world, the night sky seemed to rain stars.
いつからだろう 君のことを 追いかける私がいた
I wonder when it was that I started chasing after you.
どうかお願い 驚かないで聞いてよ 私のこの想い
Please, I beg of you, don't be shocked and listen to these feelings of mine.
あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ
That is Deneb, Altair, Vega.
君は指さす 夏の大三角
You point out the Summer Triangle.
覚えて空を見る やっと見つけた織姫様
I remember as I look at the sky, I finally found Orihime.
だけどどこだろう 彦星様 これじゃひとりぼっち
But I wonder where Hikoboshi is, at this rate you'll be all alone.
楽しげなひとつ隣の君 私は何も言えなくて
As you enjoyed yourself right next to me, I was unable to say a word.
本当はずっと君のことを どこかでわかっていた
Truth is, I've always known about you somewhere in my heart.
見つかったって 届きはしない だめだよ 泣かないで
Even if found, it wouldn't reach you. It's no use, don't cry.
そう言い聞かせた 強がる私は臆病で
That's what I told myself, acting tough while being a coward,
興味がないようなふりをしてた けど胸を突く痛みは増していく
pretending I didn't care, but the pain stabbing my chest kept growing.
まあそうか 好きになるって こういうことなんだね
I see, so falling in love is what this feels like.
どうしたい? 言ってごらん 心の声がする
What do you want? Tell me, my heart's voice says.
君の隣がいい 真実は残酷だ
I want to be by your side. Reality is so cruel.
言わなかった 言えなかった 二度と戻れないあの夏の日
I didn't say it, I couldn't say it, to those summer days that will never return.
いつもどおりのある日の事
That day was the same as any other.
君は突然立ち上がり言った
Suddenly, you stood up and said,
「今夜星を見に行こう」
"Let's go look at the stars tonight."
「たまには良いこと言うんだね」
"You say something good once in a while."
なんてみんなして言って笑った
Everyone laughed and said that.
おー、聞かせて
Oh, let me hear it...
強がる私は臆病で
I act tough, but I'm a coward,
興味がないようなふりをしていた
acting as if I had no interest.
だけど…
Even so...
胸を刺す痛みは増していく
The pain stabbing my chest grows stronger.
ああ、そうか 好きになるってこういうことなんだね
Ah, I see... so this is what it means to fall in love.
大人なんだね
You're so grown up...
どうしたい? 言ってごらん
"What do you want? Tell me."
心の声がする
A voice from my heart speaks.
君の隣がいい
I want to be by your side.
真実は残酷だ
Reality is so cruel.
言わなかった 言えなかった
I didn't say it, I couldn't say it.
二度と戻れない
We can never go back.
あの夏の日のきらめく星
To those glittering stars of that summer day.
今でも思い出せるよ
I can still remember them.
笑った顔も 怒った顔も
Your smiling face, your angry face,
大好きでした
I loved them all so much.
おかしいよね わかっていたのに
Isn't it strange? Even though I knew,
君の知らない 私だけの秘密
it's a secret known only to me, that you never knew.
夜を越えて 遠い思い出の君が
Across the night, you from distant memories
指をさす 無邪気な声で
point with an innocent voice.
夜空を見上げ 一人 ほうき星を見たの
Alone, I looked up at the night sky and saw a shooting star.
一瞬で弾けては 消えてしまったけど
It burst and vanished in the blink of an eye.
あなたのこと想うと 胸が痛くなるの
My heart aches whenever I think about you.
今すぐ逢いたいよ だけど空は飛べないから
I want to see you right now, but I can't fly across the sky.
もしあたしが ほうき星になれたなら
If I could become a shooting star,
空駆け抜け 飛んでいく
I'd dart across the sky and fly away.
どんな明日が来ても この想いは強い
No matter what tomorrow brings, my feelings remain strong.
だからほうき星 ずっと壊れないよ
So my shooting star will never break apart.
雨が降って嫌だと ぼやいていた時に
When I complained about the rain,
あなたが言ったこと 今でも覚えている
I still remember what you told me.
雨の後の夜空は 綺麗に星が出る
After the rain, stars shine so brightly in the night sky.
それを考えると 雨も好きになれるよねと
Thinking about that makes me love the rain too.
もしあたしが ほうき星になれたなら
If I could become a shooting star,
溢れる光降らすよ いつも悲しい時
I'd shower down overflowing light whenever you feel sad.
夜空見るあなたが 笑顔になるように
So that when you look at the night sky, you'll smile.
あなたは いつも 一人
You're always all by yourself,
何かと戦っている
fighting some battle,
傍にいることしか
and all I can do for you
あたしにはできないけど
is be by your side, but...
もしあたしが
If I could become
ほうき星になれたならば
a shooting star,
空駆け抜け 飛んでいく
I'd dart across the sky and fly,
きっと...
I'm sure...
届く この一瞬の光で
It'll reach you with this brief light,
あなたのイマ照らし 空を巡ろう
illuminating your present, I'll tour the skies.
あたしが ほうき星になれたならば
If I could become a shooting star,
もしあたしが ほうき星になれたならば
きっと傍にいてあげる どんな時も
I'll be right by your side, no matter when.
地上の星
[Title: Chijou no Hoshi]
風の中のすばる
In the wind, the Pleiades,
砂の中の銀河
in the sand, the Milky Way.
みんな何処へ行った
Where did everyone go,
見送られることもなく
without even a send-off?
草原のペガサス
In the fields, Pegasus,
街角のヴィーナス
on the street corner, Venus.
みんな何処へ行った
Where did everyone go,
見守られることもなく
without even being watched over?
地上にある星を 誰も覚えていない
The stars on the earth are forgotten by all.
人は空ばかり見てる
People only look to the skies.
つばめよ 高い空から教えてよ 地上の星を
Swallows high in the air, tell me of the stars on the earth!
つばめよ 地上の星は今 何処にあるのだろう
Swallows, where are the stars on the earth right now?
名立たるものを追って 輝くものを追って
Chasing after fame, chasing after things that shine,
人は氷ばかり掴む
people catch nothing but ice.
名立たるものを追って 輝くものを追って
Chasing after fame, chasing after things that shine,
人は氷ばかり掴む
people catch nothing but ice.
つばめよ 高い空から教えてよ 地上の星を
Swallows high in the air, tell me of the stars on the earth!
つばめよ 地上の星は今 何処にあるのだろう
Swallows, where are the stars on the earth right now?
名立たるものを追って 輝くものを追って
Chasing after fame, chasing after things that shine,
人は氷ばかり掴む
people catch nothing but ice.
名立たるものを追って 輝くものを追って
Chasing after fame, chasing after things that shine,
人は氷ばかり掴む
people catch nothing but ice.
風の中のすばる
In the wind, the Pleiades,
砂の中の銀河
in the sand, the Milky Way.
みんな何処へ行った
Where did everyone go?
月灯り ふんわり 落ちてくる 夜は
On nights when the moonlight comes down nice and soft...
ツバメよ 遠い空から
O swallow, from the distant sky,
教えてよ 地上の星を
tell me where the star on earth is.
ツバメよ 地上の星は
O swallow, where is the star on earth
今どこにあるのだろう
now located?
月灯り ふんわり 落ちてくる 夜は
On nights when the moonlight comes down nice and soft,
貴方のことばかり
you are the only thing on my mind.
考えても考えてもつきることもなく
No matter how much I think, it never ends.
月灯り ふんわり 落ちてくる 夜は
On nights when the moonlight comes down nice and soft,
貴方と2人きり
I want to be all alone with you,
海のはてへと続く 月の路歩きたい
and walk the moonlit path to the edge of the sea.
南風が ほほをなでてく
The southern breeze gently brushes my cheek,
やさしい手のひらのように
like the palm of a gentle hand.
体中が 貴方色した
My whole body has turned your color,
夕闇に そまりそうで
as if swallowed by the twilight.
風にのせ 伝えたい
I want to carry it on the wind and tell you,
そんな想い一人抱きしめる
holding all these feelings close to my heart.
月灯り ふんわり 落ちてくる 夜は
On nights when the moonlight comes down nice and soft,
せつない言葉だけ
only heartbreaking words fall.
何度でも何度でもくりかえす波のように
Like waves repeating over and over again,
ありふれた 小さな恋の物語
this ordinary, little love story
エピローグだけみたい
feels like just an epilogue.
まっ白なページに笑顔のあなたがほしい
I want your smiling face on this blank page.
会わないでいられる恋なら
If this is a love where we can go without meeting,
いっそ気楽でいいよね
then maybe being carefree is fine.
新しい朝がくるたびに
Every time a new morning comes,
ため息で夢がおわる
my dreams end with a sigh.
風にのせ 伝えたい
I want to carry it on the wind and tell you,
そんな想い一人抱きしめる
holding all these feelings close to my heart.
I hold those feelings all alone to my chest
月灯りふんわり落ちてくる夜は
On nights when the moonlight comes down nice and soft,
貴方のことばかり
you can be the one thing running through my mind
考えても考えてもつきることもなく woo...
and it never gets old...
月灯りふんわり落ちてくる夜は
On nights when the moonlight comes down nice and soft,
貴方と2人きり
I'd like to be all alone with you
海のはてへと続く月の路歩きたい
and walk down the moon's path to the end of the beach
ゴメンね 素直じゃないね
I'm sorry, I'm not being honest,
夢の中なら言える
but I can say it in my dreams.
思考回路はショート寸前
My thought process is on the verge of short-circuiting,
今すぐ 会いたいよ
I want to see you right now.
泣きたくなるような moonlight
Moonlight that makes me want to cry,
電話も出来ない midnight
I can't even make a phone call midnight.
だって純情 どうしよう
Because I'm so innocent, what should I do?
ハートは万華鏡
My heart is a kaleidoscope.
月の光に 導かれて 何度も 巡り会う
Guided by the moonlight, we meet again and again.
星座の瞬き数え 恋の行方占う
Counting the twinkling of constellations, predicting love's future.
同じ地球に生まれたの ミラクル・ロマンス
Born on the same earth, a miracle romance.
もう一度 ふたりで weekend 神様 かなえて happy-end
One more weekend together, god grant me a happy ending.
現在過去未来も あなたに首ったけ
I'm crazy about you in the present, past and future.
出会った時の 懐かしい まざし 忘れない
I'll never forget the nostalgic look you gave me when we first met.
幾千万の星から あなたを見つけられる
Finding you out of the millions of stars,
偶然もチャンスに変える 生き方が好きよ
I love the way of life turning coincidences into chances.
不思議な奇跡クロスして 何度も 巡り会う
A mysterious miracle crosses paths and we meet again and again.
星座の瞬き数え 恋の行方占う
Counting the twinkling of constellations, predicting love's future.
同じ地球に生まれたの ミラクル・ロマンス
Born on the same earth, a miracle romance.
信じているの ミラクル・ロマンス
I believe in a miracle romance.
幾千万の星から あなたを見つけられる
Finding you out of the millions of stars,
偶然もチャンスに変える 生き方が好きよ
I love the way of life turning coincidences into chances.
不思議な奇跡クロスして 何度も 巡り会う
A mysterious miracle crosses paths and we meet again and again.
星座の瞬き数え 恋の行方占う
Counting the twinkling of constellations, predicting love's future.
同じ地球に生まれたの ミラクル・ロマンス
Born on the same earth, a miracle romance.
信じているの ミラクル・ロマンス
I believe in a miracle romance.
幾千万の星から あなたを見つけられる
Finding you out of the millions of stars,
偶然もチャンスに変える 生き方が好きよ
I love the way of life turning coincidences into chances.
不思議な奇跡クロスして 何度も 巡り会う
A mysterious miracle crosses paths and we meet again and again.
信じているの ミラクル・ロマンス
I believe in a miracle romance.
2年生、バカは一人ここの町の空見上げる
Sophomore, the idiot is all alone, looking up at the sky of this town.
サボり学生パジャマ着てる夏休みが来ずに中退
A skipping student, wearing pajamas, summer vacation came and went without graduating.
地球で宇宙人なんてあだ名でも宇宙の待ち合わせ室には
Even with a nickname like 'alien on Earth', in the universe's meeting room
もっと変なあなたがいたの受信しているかなと接続してみると
there was someone even weirder: you. Wondering if you're receiving, when I try to connect.
みんなが避ける中でぱちくり見ているあなたがいたから
Among everyone avoiding me, you were there blinking and watching.
テレパシする気持ちが電波が違っても
Even if our telepathic feelings and radio waves are different,
きっとね何か掴んでくれてるあなたの事が好き
I'm sure you've grasped onto something, I like you.
何が何だか得して得してよ
What is going on, give me some good deals!
あなたのことが好き
I love you so much!
こんな不安でバイトできない
I can't work part-time with anxiety like this!
会話できない そら見上げる
Can't hold a conversation, looking up at the sky.
サボりがこくて
Skipping out...
パジャマ着てる夏休みが
Summer vacation wearing pajamas
五月雨中退 社会で
dropping out in early summer in society
宇宙人なんて踊っても 宇宙の
Even if an alien dances, in space...
待ち合わせ 秘密で
meeting in secret
エビも度々めぐり会えるよね
Shrimp will meet again and again, right?
愛してくれるかなと
Wondering if you'll love me
くるっとにしてみようと
trying to turn around
みんなが避ける中で
In the middle of everyone avoiding me
パチこで見ている あなたがいたから
Because you were there watching intently
テレパシー送る気持ちが
The feeling of sending telepathy
電波が近くても
even if the radio waves are close
きっとね 何か得して得してよ
Surely, give me some good deals!
あなたのことが好き
I love you so much!
受信してくれるのかなと
Wondering if you'll receive it
心配してるんです
I'm worried
なんだかんだでそばにいてくれる
You're by my side despite everything
あなたが好き
I love you!
そんなあなたのことが好き
I love that kind of you!
そんなあなたのことが好きなんだ
I really love that kind of you!
そんなあなたのことが好き
I love that kind of you!
きっとね 年をとってもできないの
Surely, even as I get older, I won't be able to do it.
ケロッ ケロッ ケロッ いざ進め〜っ
Kero kero kero, now advance!
地球侵略せよ
Invasion of Earth!
ケッケロッケロ 傘持って出かけた日には いつも晴れ
Whenever I go out with an umbrella, it's always sunny!
「気をつけ〜ッ、目を食いしばれッ！」
Attention, grit your teeth!
カレーのライスを炊き忘れ
Forgot to cook the curry rice!
閉まるドア 小指はさんだ 飛び乗ったら行き先違う
Caught my pinky in the closing door, hopped on and the destination is wrong!
社員旅行はケロン
Company trip to Keron
買った方が安いね 晩のおかずッ！
Side dish for dinner is cheaper bought!
ピロッ ピロッ ピロッ 突撃はぁ
Piro piro piro, charge is...
動く歩道で行け
Go on the moving sidewalk!
早寝して早寝して早寝して早寝して また二度寝する
Sleep early, and go back to sleep!
「全体〜ッ 止まれッ、回れッ、お手をッ！！」
Squad, halt, turn around, give your paw!!
嫌われたいのに愛される
Loved even though I want to be disliked
いらないもの 買った大バーゲン
A huge bargain buying things I don't need
ほしいものあると お金がない
When there's something I want, I have no money
四の五の言えよケロン
Don't make excuses, Keron
あ、カミナリ鳴っても隠すヘソがないッ！！！
Ah, even if thunder rumbles, I have no belly button to hide!
熱きこの血潮と
With this passionate blood
胸に刻まれし闘魂
and fighting spirit carved in our chest
永遠に勝ち誇れ 我らがケロン！
Triumph eternally, we are Keron!
熱きこの血潮と
With this passionate blood
胸に刻まれし闘魂
and fighting spirit carved in our chest
永遠に勝ち誇れ 愛しき星よ
Triumph eternally, beloved star
我らがケロン！
We are Keron!
「全体〜ッ、止まっちゃダメッ！！」
Squad, don't stop!!
ゲロッケロッケロ高らかに 勝利のオタケビを
Loudly let out the battle cry of victory
はりきって 電話に出たら ファクシミリ
Enthusiastically answered the phone, only to find a fax machine
“Heisei”は本日はよりケロン元年でありま〜っす！！
“Heisei” is from today Year One of Keron!!
四角いトコロは丸く掲げ
Sweep the square places round
水かけ 汗かけ
Splashing, sweating,
ベソっかけ
crying tears,
歯みがきなら イチゴの香り
Brushing teeth with strawberry scent,
ケロンは宇宙一、たぶん
Keron is the best in the universe, probably!
ああ 駅からの5分は 実は15分っ!!!
Ah, a 5-minute walk from the station is actually 15!
それじゃあ ソルジャー お疲れさんっ!!
So soldiers, good job today!!
ケロッ！ケロっ！ ケロッ！ケロっ！
Kerotto! Kerotto! Kerotto! Kerotto!
ケロッ！！
Kerotto!!
手を合わせて 見つめるだけで
Simply by putting hands together and staring
愛し合える 話もできる
We can love and talk to each other
くちづけするより甘く
Sweeter than a kiss,
ささやき聞くより強く
Stronger than a whisper,
飲みたくなったら お酒
If I want a drink, a cocktail,
眠たくなったら ベッド
If I want to sleep, a bed,
次から次へと さし出すあなた
You offer them to me one after another.
信じられないことばかりあるの
There are only incredible things happening,
もしかしたら もしかしたら そうなのかしら
Could it be, could it really be so?
それでもいいわ 近頃少し 地球の男にあきたところよ
But that's fine, lately I've grown a bit tired of Earth men!
ああ 突然 オレンジ色の
Ah, suddenly in orange color,
ああ 光が私をつつみ
Ah, a light envelops me,
夢見る気持ちにさせて どこへさらって行くわ
Making me feel like dreaming, carrying me away somewhere.
やっぱりそうなの 素敵なあなた
You really are such a wonderful person,
信じられないことでしょうけれども
Even though it's hard to believe,
嘘じゃないの 嘘じゃないの 本当のことよ
It's no lie, no lie, it's the absolute truth!
それでもいいわ 近頃少し
But that's fine, lately I've grown a bit
地球の男にあきたところよ
tired of Earth men!
U.F.O.
でも私は 確かめたいの
But I want to make sure of it—
その素顔を 一度は見たい
I want to see your true face just once!
鏡にうつしてみたり
Reflected in a mirror,
光をあててもみたり
Lit up by a beam of light,
それでもあなたは 普通のあなた
Yet you still look just like an ordinary person.
ああ 突然 オレンジ色の
Ah, suddenly in orange color,
ああ 光が私をつつみ
Ah, a light envelops me,
夢見る気持ちにさせて どこへさらって行くわ
Making me feel like dreaming, carrying me away somewhere.
やっぱりそうなの 素敵なあなた
You really are such a wonderful person,
信じられないことでしょうけれども
Even though it's hard to believe,
嘘じゃないの 嘘じゃないの 本当のことよ
It's no lie, no lie, it's the absolute truth!
それでもいいわ 近頃少し 地球の男にあきたところよ
But that's fine, lately I've grown a bit tired of Earth men!
嘘じゃないの 嘘じゃないの
It's no lie, no lie,
本当のことよ
It's the absolute truth!
それでもいいわ 近頃少し
But that's fine, lately I've grown a bit
地球の男にあきたところよ
tired of Earth men!
U.F.O.
僕らの生まれてくる ずっとずっと前にはもう
Long, long before we were born,
アポロ11号は 月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon,
みんながチェック入れてる限定の 君の腕時計はデジタル仕様
Yet your limited edition watch that everyone checks out is digital—
Your limited-edition watch that everyone checks out is digital—
それって僕よりはやく進むって本当かい? ただ壊れてる
Is it really running faster than mine, or is it just broken?
空を覆う巨大な広告塔には 美人が意味ありげな微笑 赤い赤い口紅でさし…
Up on the billboard that blocks out the sky, a beautiful woman gives a sly smile with her red, red lipstick...
僕らの生まれてくる ずっとずっと前にはもう
Long before we were born...
アポロ11号は月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon.
みんながチェック入れてる限定の君の腕時計はデジタル仕様
Everyone's check is limited to your digital watch.
それって僕よりはやく進むって本当?ただ壊れてる
Is it faster than mine, or is it just broken?
空を覆う巨大な広告塔には
The huge advertising tower that covers the sky
ビジョンが意味ありげなビショウ赤い赤い口紅でさぁ
gives a sly smile with her red, red lipstick.
僕らの生まれてくる ずっとずっと前にはもう
Long before we were born...
アポロ11号は月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon.
僕らはこの街がまだジャングルだった頃から
Since back when this town was still a jungle,
変わらない愛のかたち探してる
we've been searching for an unchanging love.
大統領の名前なんてさ覚えなくてもいいけれど
It's okay if you don't remember the president's name,
せめて自分の信じてた夢くらいはどうにか覚えていて
at least remember the dreams you once believed in.
地下を巡る情報に振り回されるのはビジョンが曖昧なんデショウ
Is it because our vision is too vague?
頭ん中バグっちゃってさぁ
My head's all buggy.
僕らの生まれてくる もっともっと前にはもう
Long before we were born...
アポロ計画はスタートしてたんだろ?
The Apollo project had already begun, right?
本気で月に行こうって考えたんだろね
I wonder if they really thought they could go to the moon.
なんだか愛の理想みたいだね
It's like an idealistic love.
このままのスピードで世界が回ったら
If the world keeps turning at this speed,
アポロ100号はどこまで行けるんだろう
how far will Apollo 100 be able to go?
離れ離れになった悲しい恋人たちのラヴ・メール・フロム・ビナスなんて素敵ね
Long-distance couples sending love emails from Venus sounds so romantic.
僕らの生まれてくる ずっとずっと前にはもう
Long before we were born...
アポロ11号は月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon.
僕らはこの街がまだジャングルだった頃から
Since back when this town was still a jungle,
変わらない愛のかたち探してる
we've been searching for an unchanging love.
このままのスピードで世界が回ったら
If the world keeps turning at this speed,
アポロ105号はどこまで行けるんだろう
how far will Apollo 105 be able to go?
離ればなれになっちゃった悲しい恋人たちの
Since we became strangers,
ラヴ・メロム・ビナスなんて素敵ね
love emails from Venus sound so wonderful.
僕らの生まれてくる ずっとずっと前にはもう
Long before we were born...
アポロ11号は月に行ったっていうのに
Apollo 11 had already gone to the moon.
僕らはこの街がまだジャングルだった頃から
Since back when this town was still a jungle,
変わらない愛のかたち探してる
we've been searching for an unchanging love.
わぁい！このあとは4周年記念グッズのお知らせがあるのら！
Yay! Now, let's announce the 4th Anniversary Goods!
ででーん！1つめはこちら、ームギャラクシーアクリルジオラマスタンドなのだ！
Tada! First is the Moon Galaxy Acrylic Diorama Stand!
今回の宇宙や月や星をテーマに、かんざきぱんぱに描き下ろしていただきましたー！
Created by Kanzaki Pompu featuring a cosmic, moon, and star theme.
ルーナイトがはしごを登ってるのがかわいいのらー！
Lunait climbing up the ladder is just too cute!
そして2つめはこちら、ルーナのおめめのアイマスクなのだ！
And second is the Luna Eye Mask!
お口がちょっと開いてるかわいい表情のルーナたんなのだ！
Featuring a slightly open-mouthed cute expression.
アイマスクとして使うもよし、机の上に置いておくだけでもルーナたんと目目が合うのらね！
It matches Luna-tan's expression when you wear it to sleep or display it!
そして3つめはこちら、ルーナの2WAYネックピローなのだ！
Third is the Luna 2WAY Neck Pillow!
こちらはクッションとネックピローで2種類使い分けができるのら！
It easily switches between a neck pillow and a cushion.
どっちの状態でもルーナたんがふんだんにちりばめられているのらよ！
Luna-tan is packed with comfort in either form!
ルーナつのおめめのアイマスクと合わせてお部屋で使ってほしいのら！
Use it together with the eye mask in your room!
そして4つめはこちら、ルーナの4周年記念Tシャツなのだ！
And fourth is the Luna 4th Anniversary T-shirt!
そでにピンクのポイントカラーと王冠と文字のシンプルデザインで作ったので
Featuring pink accents and a simple, stylish design.
あ、どこでも着やすいかなと思うなら、
Ah, if you think it's easy to wear anywhere,
2023年の誕生日グッズでルームライトパーカーを作ったので、合わせれてきてくれたらうれしいなら。
I'd be happy if you wore them together with the room light parka from my 2023 birthday merch.
最後に、フルセット購入してくれた全員に直筆サイン付きのポストカードがついてきます。
Lastly, everyone who purchases the full set will receive a postcard with a handwritten signature.
箔押し複製メッセージも読んじゃうならね！
You can also read the foil-stamped duplicate message!
4周年記念グッズはこの後21時からホロライブの公式ショップにて販売されるなら。
The 4th anniversary merch will be sold on the official Hololive shop starting at 21:00.
この後SNSの方でもお知らせもします。またこの配信の概要欄にも記載しておくので、ぜひぜひ購入してみんなのおうちにうなたを置いて欲しいのなよ。
I'll announce it on SNS too, and put the link in the description, so please buy it and put Unata in your homes!
みんな、ここまで見てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for watching this far!
もう1回アナウンスするけど、この後グルグル回る回るのMVが公開されるので、みんな見てなよ！
I'll announce it one more time, but the MV for "Guru Guru Mawaru Mawaru" will be released after this, so everyone check it out!
みなみな見てね！忘れたためのなよー。
Everyone, everyone watch it! Don't forget, okay?
さらば 地球 よ
Farewell, Earth,
旅立つ 船 は
the ship setting sail
宇宙戦艦ヤマト
Space Battleship Yamato.
宇宙 の 彼方 イスカンダル へ
To Iskandar in the far reaches of space,
運命 背負い 今 とび立つ
carrying our destiny, we take off now.
必ず
We'll definitely
ここ へ 戻って 来る と
return here,
手 を ふる 人 に 笑顔 で 答え
answering with a smile those waving goodbye.
銀河 を はなれ
Leaving the galaxy,
イスカンダル へ
to Iskandar,
はるばる のぞむ 宇宙戦艦ヤマト
longing for the journey, Space Battleship Yamato.
さらば 地球 よ
Farewell, Earth,
愛する 人 よ
to my loved ones,
宇宙戦艦ヤマト
Space Battleship Yamato.
地球 を 救う 使命 を 帯びて
Carrying the mission to save the Earth,
戦う 男 燃える ロマン
fighting men, burning with passion.
誰か が これ を やらねば ならぬ
Someone has to take this on,
期待 の 人 が 俺たち ならば
if we're the ones with hope.
銀河 を はなれ
Leaving the galaxy,
イスカンダル へ
to Iskandar,
はるばる のぞむ 宇宙戦艦ヤマト
longing for the journey, Space Battleship Yamato.
4周年記念ライブ
見てくれてありがとう〜♡
4th Anniversary Live
Thank you for watching~♡
いつもルナイトがそばに居てくれるから
んなたんは頑張れてるのち！！
Because the Luna-knights are always by my side,
Nnatan is able to do her best!!
どうか姫森ルーナのこれからを
ル〜ナイトに見届けてほしぃのら！！
Please keep watching over Himemori Luna's future,
Luna-knights!!
大好きななの♪♡
I love you so much♪♡